# **Abhinav Deep Rastogi**

🔀 rastogi.abhinav8@gmail.com 📞 +91 8869969818 😲 Pune, India in in/iamcrazyabhi 😱 devgrammer

Final year student by metier and developer by passion. 2+ years of getting through the field of Computer Science with a good hands-on experience at Full Stack MERN Development, C++, Python, and Algorithms. Besides, I'm a self-taught Graphics and UI Designer with 2+ years of experience added on with sound qualities of team management and leadership.



#### EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, Bharati Vidyapeeth (Deemed to be) University, College of Engineering Jul 2017 – present | Pune, India

Diploma in Network Security,

2017 – present | Pune, India

Bharati Vidyapeeth (Deemed to be) University, College of Engineering

Apr 2013 - Apr 2014 | Kaushambi, India

Senior Secondary (Science with Mathematics),

Apr 2011 - Apr 2012 | Kaushambi, India

Dr. Rizvi Springfield School

Higher Secondary (Science with Mathematics),

Dr. Rizvi Spring Field School

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Head of Design, Entrepreneurship Development Cell, BVUCOEP

Web Developer Intern, Mkt Digital Solutions

**Software Developer Virtual Intern, JP Morgan Chase & Co.** 

Design Team Lead, DevFest'19, Google Developer Group, Pune

Graphic Designer, C32Medialabs

Manager (Design), Entrepreneurship Development Cell, BVUCOEP

Associate, Entrepreneurship Development Cell, BVUCOEP

Jul 2019 – present | Pune, India May 2020 - Jul 2020 | Mexico, Remote

Jun 2020 – Jun 2020 | Remote

Sep 2019 - Oct 2019 | Pune, India

Apr 2019 – Jun 2019 | Pune, India Jun 2018 – Jun 2019 | Pune, India

Jul 2017 - May 2018 | Pune, India



### **SKILLS**

#### **Web Developement**

ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJs, Mongodb, Webpack, Redux, Babel, TailWind CSS, Bootstrap

**UI Designing** Adobe XD, Figma, Principle

**Core Computing** 

C++, Python



#### **PROJECTS**

**Foodlo,** An contactless menu ordering progressive web app.

- Implemented using React JS & Hooks and Redux.
- Ready to install in devices as a PWA.

**Graphic Designing & Content Creation** 

Photoshop, Illustrator & Adobe CC

- Modern Clean UI with Smooth interaction.
- Cart system to order the food.

#### SpaceBoard: Optimized with Gesture Control,

Paint in air using virtual canvas.

- Utilize the power of Computer vision .
- Use can draw in free space.
- Alternative solution for online teaching.
- Cheap & ready to use right from ur webcam.

### **Digital Menu,** A Contactless Menu for Cafe, Resturants etc.

- Digital Menu Web app fully Developed using React JS.
- React Bootstrap CSS library is utilized for better interaction
- Whatsapp chatbot integration
- Reusable Components

May 2021 – Jun 2021

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

May 2020 - Jul 2020

- Artik Circle (UI of an E-learning app)
- Virtual CFO (All over Branding Solution for a Startup)
- ESummit'19 & 20 (Overall media material of College mega event)



# **CERTIFICATES**

Programming For Everybody (University of Michigan)

Build Your First Web page using HTML and CSS. (Facebook Open Classroom)

Learning Programming with Javascript (ES6) (Facebook Open Classroom)

Building Web App with ReactJS (Facebook Open Classroom)

SpaceBoard Optimized with Gesture Control (International Journal of Science Technology & Engineering)



# **ACHIEVEMENT**

Nutanix Hybrid Cloud Scholarship, Udacity

Aug 2020

Secured Facebook Developer Circle Web Development Scholarship,

Jan 2020

Facebook Developer Circle

Secured 1st position at National School Science Congress,

Dr. Rizvi SpringField School

Feb 2014

# **INTERESTS**

Sketching

Playing Guitar

Playing Chess

Traveling



# **ORGANISATIONS**

Google Developer Group,

Aug 2017 – present | Pune, India

Design Team Lead and Overall Event Management Volunteer.

Startup Master Class, Event Cordinator and Designer

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020 | Pune, India

FIND YOUR INVESTOR, Organising Team

Mar 2020 - Mar 2020 | Pune, India



#### **LANGUAGES**

**English** 

**Full Professional Proficiency** 

**Full Professional Proficiency**